Guide to the Cornell University Crew records, 1871-2013.
Cornell University Crew records, 1871-2013.
- Series III. Photographs
  - Florida winter training, group photos, 1997-2001 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - 1955 Intercollegiate Rowing Association Champions Lake Onondaga Syracuse (Box 19)
  - Cornell Ltw. Crew defeats Nottingham and Union Rowing Club, July 1, 1967 (Box 19)
  - Head of the Charles, Molesey Boat Club Championship Fours – signed by Ron Arlas, Rick Spiewak and Dick Kruger, 1993 (Box 19)
  - 1990 Women’s Novice Crew (Box 19)
  - Doris Robison dedicates the Robison Shell House for Cornell Women, September 1979 (Box 19)
  - Coach Pete White instructs novices in basics of rowing stroke, Undated (Box 19)
  - Christening of the Second Shell in the Cornell Women’s Fleet, May 1977 (Box 19)
  - National Collegiate Champions, Lake Wingra Madison, Wisconsin, June 4, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Christening the Walter W. Schlaepfer, April 27, 1963 (Box 19)
  - Eastern Sprints, 1992-1995, 1998 (Box 19)
  - Freshmen 8, 2013 (Box 19)
  - 2006 Cornell Lwt., Junior Varsity, Eastern Sprints Champions (Box 19)
  - 2006 Cornell Lwt., Varsity, Eastern Sprints Champions/Lwt. Varsity IRA Champions/Henley Royal Regatta Temple Cup Finalists (Box 19)
  - 2007 Cornell Lwt., Varsity, Silver Medalists Eastern Sprints Regatta/ Varsity IRA Champions/Henley Royal Regatta Temple Cup Runner Up (Box 19)
  - 2008 Cornell Lwt., Varsity, Eastern Sprints Champions/IRA National Lwt. Champions/Henley Royal Regatta Semi Finalists (Box 19)
  - Cornell Crew Banquet, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Lightweight Individual Portraits, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Princeton vs. Cornell, April 1988 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Men's Crew, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - John P. Creel Jr., August 1994 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Women's Crew, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Women's Crew, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Intercollegiate Rowing Association (includes negatives), 1998 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Reunion Weekend, June 1998 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Head of Ohio, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Cornell vs. Michigan and Syracuse, Goes Trophy, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Spectators in front of the Boathouse, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Class of '49 Reunion, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Lightweight Crew, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - IRA Pair Champions, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Lightweight Crew, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Women at Head of the Charles, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Women's Crew at Rochester Stonehurst, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Women at Head of the Fish, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Schwartz Cup, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Lightweight Freshmen, 2000-2001 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Christening of "Hummingbird" Women's 8+, April 2001 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Women's Novice 2nd Boat, April 14, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Women's Novice 2nd Boat, April 22, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Women's Varsity Training, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Novice Women, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Women's Crew vs. Virginia, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Women's Crew vs. Princeton, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Goes Trophy, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Princeton Chase, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Head of the Charles, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Women Winter Training, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Spring Crew Newsletter Photos (includes note), 2001-2002 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Men and Women's Sprints (includes negatives), 2002 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Men's Crew Fall (includes note), 2002 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Rowing Newsletter Photos, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Women's Crew, June 2003 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Cornell Crew on Lake, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Windermere Classic Redwood Shores, April 2004 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - IRA Master Win, June 4, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Lightweight Varsity Crew, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Lightweight Crew, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Heavyweight Crew, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Cornell Crew with Goes Trophy, May 2009 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Women's Crew at Princeton, Undated (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Women's Crew inside Boathouse, Undated (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Lightweight Crew at Henley, Undated (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Ice breaking (includes note), Undated (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - Lightweight Crew Individual Portraits, ca. 1985 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - "Charles P.E. von Wrangell '48" Boat Christening, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Michigan vs. Cornell Heavyweight, March 27, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - Michigan vs. Cornell Heavyweight & George Washington / Georgetown vs. Women, March 27, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Cornell Crew on Lake, April 1999 (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - Cornell Crew on Lake, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Rutgers race and Goes Cup (includes note), 1999 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - Cornell Crew, ca. 2000 (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - Women's Sprints Lake Wakamag, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - Michigan vs. Cornell Heavyweight, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 58)
  - Men and Women's Crew at Rochester, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 59)
  - Schwartz Cup (includes negatives), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 60)
  - Cornell Crew on Lake (includes note), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 61)
  - Various Crew, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 62)
  - Christening the "Violet Y. '41" shell (includes note), June 2004 (Box 20, Folder 63)
  - Rick Dyer, Mike McGuirk, and John Nunn at FISA World Masters Regatta (includes note), September 3-5, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 64)
  - Heavyweights, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 65)
  - Opening Day in Seattle, May 2005 (Box 20, Folder 66)
  - Lightweight Crew in Louisiana, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 67)
  - Men's Sprints vs. Yale and Princeton, Lightweight rowers at Princeton Chase, 2005, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 68)
  - Cornell Heavyweight wins Eastern Sprints (includes note), 1960 (Box 20, Folder 69)
  - Cornell Chronicle, May 1975 (Box 20, Folder 70)
  - Heavyweight Crew, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 71)
  - Cornell Crew, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 72)
  - Lightweight Crew (includes note), 2001 (Box 20, Folder 73)
  - Lightweight Freshmen, 2001-2002 (Box 20, Folder 74)
  - Varsity Crew rowing north on Six Mile Creek, 1898 (Box 20, Folder 75)
  - Final in Girls Interclass Race, 1921 (Box 20, Folder 76)
  - Contact Sheets and Negatives of Head of the Charles Crews, IRA Crews, EARC, and Alumni Crews, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 77)
  - Cornell Women's Crew, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 78)
  - Lightweight Crew with Coach Todd Kennett '90, May 1998 (Box 20, Folder 79)
  - Lightweight Varsity and Second Varsity Crew, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 80)
  - Lightweight Varsity, 2008 (Box 20, Folder 81)
  - Men's and Women's team photos, Undated (Box 20, Folder 82)
  - Miscellaneous Crew, Undated (Box 20, Folder 83)
  - Individual portraits, ca. 1880's-1890's (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Individual portraits, ca. 1880's-1890's (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Individual portraits, 1888-1889 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Individual portraits, 1888-1889 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Individual portraits, 1890 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Individual portraits, 1892 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Individual portraits, 1897 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - 1967 reunion (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - IRA Alumni dinner, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - The Cornell Launch at Poughkeepsie, John Hoyle and John L. Collyer on board, Undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Ken Charhut, Undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Unknown men's team reunion (includes note), Undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - On the Harlem River at New York, ca. 1800's (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Mary M. Crawford (Mrs. Edward Schuster) rowing in a single shell, June 1905 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Group photos and races, 1915 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - 1997 Reunion (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - 1997 Reunion and "VonHemert '83" christening (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Crew banquet, April 17, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - 1999 Reunion, June 1999 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - 1999 Reunion and "59' Freshmen" shell dedication, June 1999 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - "Red Storm Rising" shell dedication, June 1999 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Women's Crew with trophy, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Women's Sprints, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Teagle Hall tank building work, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Receiving trophy at Head of the Fish, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Men's Crew in Portland, November 4, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Summer scenes, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Lindseth boat photos, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - 2001-2002 Cornell Crew (1 of 4) (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 2001-2002 Cornell Crew (2 of 4) (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - 2001-2002 Cornell Crew (3 of 4) (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 2001-2002 Cornell Crew (4 of 4) (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Spring break, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Schwartz cup, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Schwartz cup, 2002-2004 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Men's Crew vs. Princeton, Undated (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Men's Crew vs. Dartmouth vs. Harvard vs. Yale, Undated (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Men's Crew in the lock, Undated (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Individual portraits, ca. 1900's (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - 1903 (?) Crew, ca. 1903 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - 2nd Freshmen Crew, 1917 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Lightweight Varsity Crew, 1920 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Letter with response regarding summer rowing program for young people (includes photos), 1973 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Men's Crew old fashioned parody photo, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - 1982 season review with photos (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - 1989 Women's National Champions (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - 1991 World Championships Silver Medalists - Women's Four (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Lightweight Crew, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Varsity and Freshmen lightweight, 1992-1993 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Virginia MacDonald Lindseth and John W. MacDonald boats, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - Launch being launched; Loading boats and laundry out to dry; Christening of "Big Red" launch, Undated (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - Unknown Crew in black-face, Undated (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Men's Crew vs. Yale, Undated (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Mens Crew running with oars, Undated (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - Henley Royal Regatta, Undated (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - Class of 1938 reunion, Undated (Box 21, Folder 52)
  - Georges Cointe (Box 21, Folder 53)
  - John Hoyle (Box 21, Folder 54)
  - Todd Jesdale (Box 21, Folder 55)
  - Tony Johnson (Box 21, Folder 56)
  - David Kusick (Box 21, Folder 57)
  - Findley Meislahn (Box 21, Folder 58)
  - Douglas Neil (Box 21, Folder 59)
  - John N. Ostrom (Box 21, Folder 60)
  - Daniel Roock (Box 21, Folder 61)
  - Harrison "Stork" Sanford (Box 21, Folder 62)
    Includes Hall of Fame banquet photo
  - Negatives of Cornell's first crew in Intercollegiate competition, 1873 (Box 21, Folder 63)
  - Negatives of Henley Royal Regatta with letter from Glyn Locke to Head Coach Fin Meislahn, 1970's (Box 21, Folder 64)
  - Negatives of Men's Crew, 1970's (Box 21, Folder 65)
  - Negatives of Henley Royal Regatta and contact sheets, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 66)
  - Slides of Cornell Crew on lake with Findley Meislahn, 1976-1977 (Box 21, Folder 67)
  - Lightweight Varsity Crew, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 68)
  - Negatives of Head of the Fish, total point trophy, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 69)
  - Negatives of individual portraits, Undated (Box 21, Folder 70)
  - Negatives, miscellaneous crew, Undated (Box 21, Folder 71)
  - Unknown negative of person in a single shell, ca. 1900's (Box 21, Folder 72)
  - Charles E. Courtney's house, Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Charles E. Courtney (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Men's Crew, May 3, 1924 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of thanks to the Pennsylvania Boat Club regarding hospitality during Child's Cup contest, July 9, 1887 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Varsity Crew, 1875 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "The Henley Crew", 1895 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Men's Crew, ca. 1900's (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Men's Four, 1900, 1903 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Varsity Crew, 1911 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Olympic rowing trials, July 5, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Defeating Yale in final for Grand Challenge Cup, Henley Royal Regatta, Undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Findley Meislahn with unidentified group, Undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Dedication of "E.F. Rosey Bower", with Stork Sanford, Undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Undated Women's Crew (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Undated Men's Crew (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Men's Crew, ca. 1900's (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Varsity Crew, 1897-1898 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Varsity Crew, 1902, 1906 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Varsity Crew, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Albert R. Coffin photo, Undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Group photos, ca. 1900's (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Women's first crew - Sage College Crew/Sage Boating Club, ca. 1897 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook (contains photos), 1937-1940 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook (contains photos), 1945-1946 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook (contains photos), 1947-1948 (Box 26)
    Found loose within scrapbook: misc. newspapers, 2 pages from a different scrapbook, 1948 U.S. Olympic Team Trials program, 1947 and 1948 Poughkeepsie Regatta programs
  - Cornell Crew photos, 1999-2000; ZD-39
  - Photos HW, LW, WM, 2001-2002; ZD-40
  - Photo collage of races - contains both men and women, 1991-1999 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Photo collage of races - contains just men, 1992-1994 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - Photo collage of races - contains just men, 1995-1999 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - Photo collage of races - contains just women, 1970's, 1992-1997 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Varsity Crew, 1917 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Cornell Crew Club, yearbook photo (parody), 1949 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Collyer boathouse, Undated (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Eastern Sprints Gold Medalists, 2nd Varsity Eight, 2005 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Cornell Lightweight Crew, 1985 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - Freshmen Crew, 1899 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - Cornerstone ceremony, class of 1917 reunion, June 8, 1957 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - Class of 1894 group photograph, 1891 (Mapcase-folder 8)
  - Untitled, Undated (Box 33)
    Slides
- Series IV. Objects
  - Freshman fall regatta plaque, 1980; MU-1687 (Box 17)
  - Windermere Cup plaque, 1991; MU-1688 (Box 17)
  - Windermere Cup plaque, opening day, 1993; MU-1689 (Box 17)
  - Troy memorial trophy case plaque, gift of John L. Collyer, Undated; MU-1690 (Box 17)
  - Inter College Regatta Goblet, engraved with winning crews from 1906 through 1915, 1906-1915; MU-1708